# MARIA MANUEL

(415) 916-9449

Sacramento, CA 95691

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven lifelong learner seeking an opportunity to share knowledge, constantly learn and be challenged. Willingness to lend more than 15 years of expertise in managing multiple priorities. Eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills.

## **SKILLS**

OS: Windows, macOSDatabase: NoSQL, Access

• Software: MS Office, G Suite

CMS: WordPress

Coding: HTML, CSS, BootstrapCoding: Python, Shell, Linux

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

### M.E.D.A

 Front-end web development completed 11/2023

### CompTia

 A+ certification - expected 08/2024

#### **EDUCATION**

City College of San Francisco Expected in 12/2024

Associate of Science: Information Technology

City College of San Francisco 06/2020

Associate of Science: Health Education

# LINKS

- https://maria-manuel.com
- https://github.com/maria-manuel
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-m-443143255/

### **WORK HISTORY**

San Francisco Living Wage Coalition - Intern - Web Developer San Francisco, CA • 10/2022 - Current

- Collaborate effectively and communicate professionally with members of the development team and client.
- Shadow senior team members to learn new tasks.
- Problem-solve to determine appropriate debug/testing processes.
- Improve website functionality by updating plugins and extensions.
- Troubleshoot and conduct standup of resolved technicalities.
- Coordinate with manager to obtain content for updates/expansions.
  Make recommendations for new features based on suitability and
- alignment with business goals.Maintain 3 websites using best practices to serve diverse groups
- according to client's needs.
- Perform duties using attention to detail in design and web content using HTML and CMS.
- Collaborate in WordPress content management system.

# Volunteer Service - Caregiver

San Francisco, CA • 02/2015 - 07/2022

- Supervised and built strong relationship with seriously ill patient.
- Communicated with healthcare team to develop tailored support and improved well being of patient on an ongoing basis.
- Organized and supported activities of daily living.
- · Documented sleep and eating patterns in medical record books.

# McClellan & Corren - Workers Comp. - Legal Assistant South San Francisco, CA • 10/2013 - 01/2015

- Act independently while supporting and monitoring database by proactively administering case development.
- · Increased client satisfaction by efficiently managing case files and

- promptly addressing inquiries.
- Administered data by effectively utilizing best practices.
- Provided end-user support addressing desktop application issues.
- Assisted in management of projected workflow for rotating assistants.
- Surpassed firm objectives by cooperating with staff to implement project management initiatives and met projected deadlines by at least 1 day, ahead of schedule.
- Performed research and conferred with parties of all levels to gather, document and review information.
- Communicated effectively, verbally, and in writing as appropriate under the direction of attorneys.

# Lewis, Brisbois, Bisgaard & Smith - Workers Comp. - Legal Assistant San Francisco, CA • 11/2011 - 06/2013

- Assist non-technical staff and attorneys with support addressing desktop application issues. Served as technical liaison.
- Modified database to accurately reflect case status documentation.
- Assisted department in added responsibilities to meet team goals with a positive attitude.
- Handled multiple projects simultaneously for 3 attorneys.
- Respond to all clients professionally and courteously.
- Proofread/edited a high volume of AME/QME medical-legal records.

# Law Offices Of Mullen & Filippi - Workers Comp. - Legal Secretary San Francisco, CA • 10/2006 - 10/2011

- Use initiative as the resident expert of desktop applications by utilizing all available resources.
- · Manage and maintain pertinent legal information in the database.
- Monitored cases while observing confidentiality with extreme discretion and delegated tasks.
- Proofread/edited court correspondence and medical summaries.
- Communicated with professionals of all levels including courthouses for case status, research, and gathered information.